

seeking roles in Software Engineering in Hadoop, Big Data, Java, Scala, Python, Spring Boot, Microservices, API Gateways, Change Management, Defect Management, Quality Management, Cloud data platform, Data Streaming ,Jenkins,Docker,Putty,JIRA,Hive,Git.



Current Designation: Software Engineer Total Experience: 5 Year(s) 5 Month(s)

Current Company: TechnePlus Notice Period: 15 Days or less

Current Location: Delhi Highest Degree: MCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Gurgaon, Pune Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills:

Hadoop, Jenkins, Docker, Putty, JIRA, Hive, Git, Python, Django, pyspark, Spark, Cloudera, SCALA, MySQL, Linux, NoSQL, Java, Hiber

Mvc,J2Ee,Change Management,Requirement Gathering,Software Engineering,Defect Management,Quality

Management, AWS

Verified: Phone Number 1 Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

Summary

I am a passionate and proficient Hadoop and spark Developer with 5 years of experience in Oracle, python, Kafka, Hive, Sqoop, snowflake, UNIX shell Scripting

Total 5.7 years of experience in IT industry, extensively working in Hadoop, Big data, Kafka, Spark and Java/J2EE projects.

Hands on Experience in working with big data ecosystem technologies like Hive, Sqoop, Map Reduce.

Working experience on data Ingestion and Sqoop.

Working experience on Kafka and Kafka streaming API.

Working experience on Spark, Spark RDD, Data Set and Data Frame.

Working experience on Python and Pyspark.

Strong Knowledge of Hadoop and Hive and Hive's analytical functions.

Having programming skills in Core JAVA / J2EE with Spring, Hibernate and Web services.

Working experience on UNIX and shell scripting.

Hands-on experience in various assistant tools such as JUnit, Log4j, Ant, Maven, SVN.

Having work experience in git, Jenkins and Docker.

Work Experience

TechnePlus as Software Engineer

Jul 2020 to Till Date

working as a python Java developer with spring boot, Hibernate and web services.

Incedo as Software Engineer

Dec 2015 to Apr 2020

Project: EDH (Enterprise Data Hub) Feb 2017 - Apr 2020

Client: Cetera (U.S.)

Cetera Financial Group is a retail investment advice platform and the USA's second largest independent financial advisor network by number of advisors. The network is comprised of ten firms - four legacy Cetera-branded that collectively have about 9,500 advisers. In EDH project Different Sources of data is pushed into a Data hub which basically based on Hadoop clusters to facilitate the ad hoc reporting and analysis Developed web services for different business

components.

- Project Role:
- As a part of Data ingestion team, creating Sqoop commands to inject data from various sources like Oracle and MS-Server into HDFS and then import to snowflake cloud and using snowsgl and snowflake commands to load data in snowflake tables, and using pyspark Spark RDD, Spark APland snowflake stages and HIVE tables for analytical purpose. Also creating DDL scripts in hive to store data from different sources.
- Using snowflake stages and snowsql and snowflake database tables.
- Using pyspark for creating spark data frame and RDD on distributed data.
- Client interaction on daily basis to understand their requirements.
- Working on CI/CD process with data pipeline using Kafka and Kafka streaming.
- production support for monitoring the process.

Project: Cetera-L&R(cetera-Licensing and registration) Jan 2016- Jan 2017

Cetera Financial Group is a retail investment advice platform and the USA's second largest independent financial advisor network by number of advisors. The network is comprised of ten firms - four legacy Cetera-branded that collectively have about 9,500 advisers. In this project cetera providing the License and Registration to the Advisors. These Advisors are deal with customers for investment plans and Mutual Funds.

Working on spring MVC framework.

Working on Hibernate with JPA architecture.

Working on RESTful services for CURD operations.

Working on JSP pages for create L&R panel.

Snapdeal as Software Engineer

Feb 2015 to Nov 2015

Project: Snapdeal Admin Panel Feb 2015 ? July 2015

Client: Snapdeal

We working for our projects working on JAVA Technologies (Hibernate, Spring, MVC Model) and MySQL DBMS at Ubuntu platform with SDLC fundamentals, solve problem related to affined code, tools and related issues, update the patches connected to software development with updates on versatile platforms with related security level.

- Designed JSP ?s as per requirement.
- Applied design patterns like DAO, Factory Pattern.
- Written Spring Service interfaces and their Implementations.
- Writing Spring DAO?s and their implementations with hibernate
- Injected Spring DAO?s into Spring Services.
- Written Hibernate component used to connect to the database from Java, J2EE applications. Developing various web services to extend business functionalities.
- Worked on backend with spring and hibernate to support new users of application to meet their business needs Project: App Share July 2015 ? Nov 2015

Client: Snapdeal

Worked to implement AppShare program which targets to maximize installation and promotion of Snapdeal App and to increase customer-base. With this program user can generate a referral code and using this invite code their friends can join and can earn reward amount and they can reward their referrer also by making their first purchase from Snapdeal mobile App.

- Deployment of the applications on unix servers and testing.
- Developing rest services with java.

Education

UG: BCA (Computers) from Indira Gandhi National Open University (IGNOU) in 2008

PG: MCA (Computers) from Pondicherry University in 2012

IT Skills

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Big Data Technologies, SQL Server	
Hadoop, Sqoop, Hive, Spark, JIRA	
SQL, Pyspark, HDFS Map Reduce	

Kafka, Kafka Streaming, Java/J2EE		
Docker, Jenkins, git, Agile, Jmeter		
Putty/WinScp, Jboss server, Service-now		
AWS	2020	1 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Expert			

Affirmative Action

Work Authorization

Physically Challenged: No

Job Type: Permanent

Employment Status: Full time